<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>targetgenerator on nray</title>
    <link>https://nray-scanner.org/usage/configuration-file/targetgenerator/</link>
    <description>Recent content in targetgenerator on nray</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nray-scanner.org/usage/configuration-file/targetgenerator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>standard</title>
      <link>https://nray-scanner.org/usage/configuration-file/targetgenerator/standard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nray-scanner.org/usage/configuration-file/targetgenerator/standard/</guid>
      <description>This is the standard target generator that is probably going to be used most of the time. It takes a list of IPs, CIDR networks or domain names as targets and black list as well as a list of TCP and UDP ports to be scanned.
enabled: true Enables or disables this target generator.
targets: [] A list of targets to scan. May be (also a mix of) CIDR networks, IPs or domain names.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>certificatetransparency</title>
      <link>https://nray-scanner.org/usage/configuration-file/targetgenerator/certificatetransparency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nray-scanner.org/usage/configuration-file/targetgenerator/certificatetransparency/</guid>
      <description>The certificatetransparency streams data from certstream, a certificate transparency log stream. This allows to inspect all publicly issued certificates. Using this data, port scans may be issued against targets right after they obtain a certificate, usually during setup before any hardening or default password changes have been in place.
This may come in handy for bug bounties - nray authors BTW love to get invited for a coffee</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ldap</title>
      <link>https://nray-scanner.org/usage/configuration-file/targetgenerator/ldap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nray-scanner.org/usage/configuration-file/targetgenerator/ldap/</guid>
      <description>The ldap target generator allows to connect to a ldap server in order to identify scan targets. Especially in Active Directory environments this is really useful since computer objects have a dNSHostName property and Domain Controllers usually act also as DNS servers that can be queried via LDAP.
enabled: false Enables or disables this target generator.
ldapSearchString: &amp;quot;(objectCategory=computer)&amp;quot; The ldap search to perform for selecting objects. In Active Directory environments, (objectCategory=computer) can be used to select all computer objects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>